...full of memories.
But death is a
greedy visitor.
It never happens just once.
He came back...
and took his best friend with him.
I saw the boy's heart break.
And then... I made a vow.
You'll never lose anyone again.
I worked.
I was spending more and more time
in the basement.
A place off-limits to James.
The days turned into weeks.
Creating something.
Something just for him.
Something that will never say goodbye.
Something that will
never belong to death.
Dialogue Translation &
Timing: Sparta
Not today. thank you.
Oh my God. not again.
Come on. that joke is so old
it should be in a nursing home.
Um... hi. James.
How does he do it?
He had a rough time earlier.
but I think he'll be okay.
What about you?
I'm fine... as much as I can be.
Yes. thank you.
Hi.
Thank you for
taking care of him. my love.
Grab your coat. kid.
A little fresh air
will do us good.
It's always hard to lose
someone you love.
Your mother... and now
your best friend.
Grandpa. have you ever been scared?
What happens next?
I mean... when we die?
The only thing that worries me is you.
I wish Zack were still here.
I don't feel the same way anymore.
Or maybe he's still here.
I believe that what
makes you who you are.
It remains here even as it permeates everything
that surrounds us.
You've grown up a little more
than I thought. Rames.
I've seen your nose
get bigger. just like your dad's.
Look up.
What do you see?
Um... little stars?
There are more
things in the sky
and on earth.
more than you can imagine.
This means that life is full
of endless possibilities.
Are you okay?
Don't worry.
Are you sure?
We need to go home soon.
I have something really exciting
to show you tomorrow.
Are you sure you
don't remember anything else?
James?
Who are you talking to?
Come downstairs.
There's someone here
I'd like you to meet.
Anyone?
Come on.
Is that what I think
it is?
That's him.
Where is it?
I think he's embarrassed.
Come outside.
I want you to meet someone.
He's the boy
I was telling you about.
Yeah... him.
You're the first person
he's ever seen.
Except for me.
I think he wants
to be your friend.
Please. stop!
Listen to me. James.
What the hell was that?
Calm down and watch your head.
It's crazy.
It's not a thing.
It's someone. James.
It's a lifetime.
Things aren't
always what they seem.
What are you talking about?
I know it's hard
to believe. but
Believe me. in time
you'll come to understand.
I didn't mean to scare you.
I just thought you
could use a friend.
I know you need him.
A friend?
With this thing?
This could be
good for both of you.
How long has he been down there?
It's the only thing he knows anymore.
Why don't you talk to him?
My name is James.
I'm Pinocchio.
Are we friends?
Maybe.
We'll see.
James.
You can't tell
anyone about this.
Do you understand?
You won't get anything from me.
Captain James.
Hold your ground!
Did you get it?
Make your move.
Is that me?
Yes.
Now...
It's just a dog in here.
That's biology.
What is biology?
That's what explains
what makes you different from me.
Instruments and other things.
What else makes us different?
Teeth. eyes. hair. skin...
so many things.
I want to be just like you.
Believe me...
You don't want that.
You're way ahead of me.
What is this?
My heart will protect me.
You are my heart.
However. sometimes...
James.
You can't.
I want James's baby.
He'll go to school tomorrow.
People won't take it well.
Because I don't have a penis?
No.
I don't know how to answer that.
The world isn't ready for you.
Not at all.
So... a hundred kilograms?
That's nonsense. man.
Lean muscles.
Just hidden.
He once tried something like a diet.
I can help you with that.
Would you do it?
I can easily help you
lose five kilograms.
How?
I'll just cut off your right hand.
My head...
Come closer.
My fractures are hurting.
Do you speak?
Who else would tell you the truth?
He's hiding.
What are you?
I am your wooden mother.
Geppetto may
have carved our bodies...
but I will shape
your mind.
Are you trapped there?
Just like you.
I'm not trapped.
The strings may be invisible.
but you remain his puppet.
I'm not a puppet.
I'm just like James.
I'm a real boy.
Your nose gives you away.
Your creator tells you that you are real.
But she doesn't look at you the way
she looks at James.
You want his arms to hold you...
not to hide you.
Come closer. and I'll whisper to you
how to become real.
You need skin. blood. teeth. and hair.
Take them... put them on.
Yuck. that's disgusting.
Then stay locked up.
little puppet.
While James walks
in the sunlight.
Unless I've been
wrong about you.
Prove it.
Pinocchio?
There you are.
Who are they?
They are my best friends.
Best friends?
Yes. as a friend forever.
Someone you protect
and whose promises you never break.
Are we best friends?
Give me your hand.
We need to make it official first.
A super-secret handshake.
First. we clap our hands
on both sides. like this... and then...
That's... right.
Good guess.
Are you going back tomorrow?
Yes. and you're coming with me.
But first we have to make all those
promises.
No matter what happens. no one must
see you move.
She's a cutie. isn't she?
Easy.
Why are you tied up?
My father says it's
to protect me.
You have to be strong.
Here you go.
You're heavy.
No. I'm not.
Today is your first day of school
See you later. Grandpa.
See you later. kid.
Mom was late.
This is Trey.
And he stays there.
He's a real jerk.
A toilet?
James.
What does "kathiki" mean?
Um... I'll explain it to you
some other time.
I'm sorry.
I mean... is it kind of lame
or totally lame?
Ethics
Well. guys.
How do we know
what is harmful to someone?
Bad.
Each of you has
an inner conscience.
Like a compass.
Which leads you toward what you believe
is right.
Come on. let's go!
Just a minute.
I can't let you in there.
Stay here and don't cause any damage.
James. are you talking to your bag?
I'm coming.
Yes. it'll be out soon.
He's just trying to keep
his arm from getting crushed.
STAFF GYM
Up.
Down.
Don't worry. James.
No one has ever seen you.
Your best friend. Henry.
Yes.
No!
Are you okay?
Oh my God. be careful!
Oh my God!
I have to go.
Promise me you won't
tell anyone about me.
What are these used for?
There was a time when newspapers were
a mirror of society.
I don't want to be the bad guy.
This ugly guy here is chasing me.
I look exactly like him.
Yes. I know.
That means I have to
stop him and...
Don't make any noise.
Dude!
I've been looking for you all day.
Are you messing around with those dolls again?
They're not dolls.
She got a bigger one. didn't she?
Yes.
Take whatever you want.
Your grandfather is
filthy rich. anyway.
He inherited them.
Think of it as a tax.
He doesn't want to meet up. does he?
Listen. the only reason she likes you...
It's because you're a bigger loser
than your dead friend.
Hold him while
I turn everything upside down.
Screw it. James!
No!
Oh my God. I hate you!
Get off me!
I hate you!
Go fuck yourself!
Damn it!
Leave me alone!
Don't worry about it. you idiot.
I'm going to kill you.
What the hell. Tre?
You're the one who always starts it!
Man. you've got to get out of here.
All of you!
James.
They're really bad people. aren't they?
The worst.
They are all dead.
Thank you. Mia.
Come here.
Who is that little boy?
This is Pinocchio.
He's one of a kind.
What do you say—should I go find
Dudley and have him show it to us?
What do you mean. you went to the gym?
It seems that it must be
in this secret area
James. what...?
What is this?
Your grandpa made something
strange this time.
Look at that nose.
All right. guys. there's
something I wanted to show you.
Promise me that
this will stay between us?
Yes. of course.
I promise.
Thank you.
It's okay.
We can see that.
Thank you.
No way!
Okay. this is officially the
coolest and creepiest thing I've ever seen.
How do you do that?
Okay. come on. Mia. what is this?
Is it some kind of
artificial intelligence. James?
Yes. exactly.
The wires are hidden. and he has
a chip in his brain.
A brain chip?
The processor. anyway.
No matter what happens. my grandfather must
never find out that I have him.
It costs about
one million pounds.
Shit.
Sorry. guys. I have to go.
I was late for my dentist appointment.
Dude!
Listen to me!
I'll stop by right after my doctor's appointment!
It's going to hurt a lot. isn't it?
Please... Can you give me
some of those so I can sleep?
That's not possible.
Just be brave. okay?
Are you sure?
It'll be over before you know it.
Then you'll have perfect teeth.
just like mine.
Come on.
Open your mouth wide.
Ready.
This will help you a lot.
Shall we get started now?
How are you feeling. James?
I feel terrible.
You'll be just fine tomorrow.
Are you okay?
James?
Let's go? Let's go?
The hospital is calling you.
Who is it?
This is a call from Samir Hospital.
Your grandson had an accident.
Oh my God. please. let it not be him
How's it going?
Yes. that's fine.
Only superficial injuries.
But it shows signs of a mild concussion.
I think that with a little rest.
they'll be fine.
What happened?
Drunk driver.
The same guy who crashed last year. too.
And that reminds me that I need
to go see him. too.
because it's in really bad shape.
I'm going to see him.
James. please don't die.
You're my best friend.
Best friends.
Best friends look out for
each other.
Yes.
You're just saying things. Larry.
It's all in your head.
Dr. Robin.
Here you go.
Hi.
Damn it. hurry up.
Where did you go?
The paralysis is temporary.
Please. try
not to worry.
I'll go get something for the pain.
There you are.
You're the bad guy.
You're pure evil.
It's all your fault.
James is my friend.
He's my best friend.
I'll take care of him.
That's why I have to kill you.
Staying silent won't help you.
My people protect
one another.
And your fear is over.
You deserve to die.
Well then. Mr. Drunkard.
Go to hell!
The world wouldn't miss a thing
if someone like you were gone.
Why don't you just die already?
Instruments and other things.
I like it here.
I can eat this.
I'm going to become a real boy.
I'm going to be just like James.
Thank you very much.
Yes. there are so many of them.
Yeah. yeah. it's a lot of fun.
He has so many of them.
James is safe.
The era of terror is over.
For James.
It was right after the dentist.
Suddenly. he popped up out of nowhere.
Yes.
I'll call the nurse.
No. no. no.
No. it seems like I'm over it now.
Are you sure?
Yes. I'll be fine.
Are you okay. James?
We've received your test results.
and you can go now.
Is that okay?
Yes. you're perfectly fine.
You just need some rest. Okay?
Thank you.
Come on. let's take you home. kid.
I'll take your bag.
Wait.
I'll get my bag myself.
You're really strange.
How can it be so strange?
The hardest blow.
Look who's here to see you.
James. Grandpa told us everything.
All right. guys. I'm going to go get
some pizza in a little while. so don't do anything stupid.
Thank you. Grandpa.
Yeah. your... thing.
Shit!
I thought you still had it.
Remember. it's a secret.
What a load of nonsense this doll is! Oh!
I'm always active.
Do you have a leak?
They are my organs.
They make me real.
What on earth?
James. man. why is it leaking?
I'll explain it to you later.
Let's just take him back to his grandpa.
James. come on. Dudley.
Come on.
Dudley. hurry up.
Bring him here.
I have to stay
and protect you.
You can't.
Grandpa mustn't find out.
That's our secret. remember?
But you're putting yourself in danger.
James. what's all this?
You're trying to turn everything
upside down. aren't you?
Yes. Mr. James.
You think you can take me on?
Leave me alone!
Don't act like a child!
Don't you dare!
Stop!
Dudley. what?
Are these yours?
No.
Please.
I'm sorry.
When it's over. I'll come back.
I promise you that.
Hurry up.
This is in
Grandpa's safe room.
Is everything okay?
I'll be right back.
Sick.
Are you feeling sick?
No. in a good way.
I feel fine.
Okay.
You remember what we talked about. right?
Yes. Grandpa.
Great.
Don't put pressure on yourself.
Here you go. my little stick.
Come closer.
Tell your old wooden mother
what's tormenting you.
They're hiding me because I'm different.
but James is in danger.
Is he in danger?
This kid?
By whom?
From many bad people.
One of them almost killed him.
so I had to kill him.
My smart boy.
That is true love.
Was that wrong?
Bad?
Killing him?
Of course not.
You were just protecting him.
and that was only the beginning.
You know now what you have to do
about the other bad people. right?
It's better than two.
Exactly. One by one.
until they're all gone.
Then James will be safe.
And remember. if you want to become
truly authentic...
piece by piece.
to become your true self.
Yes. right here.
That'll do.
And why are we
at Geppetto's place?
Because I think Geppetto
is hiding something.
And I want to see what's hidden
in those old movies.
I was right.
I believe that the soul. life.
energy...
or whatever else you want to call it.
continues to exist after death...
and that will allow us
to outwit death.
I heard this strange crying sound.
You just have to see it.
Now that I have shaped the other human form.
evolution is proceeding more quickly.
With assistance. he is regaining
his cognitive functions.
It moves incredibly fast.
No one should touch that.
This experiment is dangerous.
It was born evil.
He has become obsessed with becoming human
and escaping from these walls.
And until...
Did you know anything about any of this?
He calls us his playthings.
Why are we going back
to all this crap?
Closed.
Yes. I think that
happened two days ago.
So far. no experiment
has retrieved
even a single
memory from Spiralife.
Until then. I can't be sure that
it is. in fact. a form of rebirth.
My next experiment.
Pinocchio.
will be exposed to external stimuli
in order to recall these memories.
Tonight she'll meet my grandson.
So. where is he?
Pinocchio!
Who are you?
My name is Cricket.
Your wooden mother
sent me to look after you.
on the right path
and to listen to your elders.
To help James?
Exactly.
The world is full of corruption that you need to
put a stop to. like the one in there.
Oh my God!
And remember. piece by piece.
we'll take whatever's left.
Everything you need to become your true self.
Thank you. Cricket.
Let's do it.
For James!
Let's make that
bitch pay for it.
She collects these.
That awful woman.
Take this!
You won't hurt James.
Okay.
How dare you!
I saw what you did to James.
You can't hide behind
those masks anymore.
This will help you.
It won't hurt at all.
Yes!
Wipe that smile
off her filthy face.
Make her say "cheese."
Thank you. Cricket.
Just pray that it's over
before you even realize it.
You'll never hurt James again.
What a horrible woman!
Yes!
All right. then.
Now let's put a smile on your face.
They're mine now.
I like a big. warm smile.
Just like yours.
James. I can't wait
to show this to James.
Pinocchio?
Oh my God!
There are some creepy things
in this room.
Why didn't you tell us. James?
You said it was a robot!
He has disappeared.
Take my phone.
What?
Why?
Hurry up. just do it.
Pinocchio?
Does it have teeth?
What are you doing?
I stop all
the bad people.
How are you going to stop them?
Everyone is always hurting you.
That's why I have to protect you.
Look!
All saints!
No. no. Pinocchio.
that's not what I meant.
What?
I need this.
That's it.
Anything else?
I'm going to kill some more people!
Oh my God!
Way to go. Dudley.
Wait!
Stop!
Come back!
Get back here. you idiot!
Stop him!
This is behind
my dentist's office.
James!
One!
Pinocchio!
I found you!
You jerk!
James!
Pick up your phone right now!
Where did you take him?
Someday you'll have to become a grown-up
woman—do you understand that?
No. stop!
Stop being such a pain!
Spastic?
You jerk!
Wait. wait!
Naughty boy!
No!
Swim. swim. swim!
I'm coming. you old goat!
Go swim. you silly lady!
I'm coming!
And I'm only three inches tall!
Give me a hand!
Stop fighting!
I'm going to send you to hell!
Be careful. Pinocchio.
Time for a science lesson.
Whack. whack. you bastard!
Help!
Hi. Logan.
Oh my God!
More stem cells
to become like James.
Teeth.
Eyes.
A lot of things.
Pinocchio!
What the hell is all this?
Damn it!
Go fuck yourself!
We did it!
Well. Dudley. should I tell them that
there's a murderous goblin on the loose?
No. he's not a murderous
kallikantzaros. okay?
He's just... trying to protect me!
Sure. James.
He's... he's a murderer.
I mean. look. it literally kills...
It literally kills... James.
This is all my fault!
James. is there anyone you can
think of who might be his next target?
Damn it!
Shit!
Trey!
Trey?
Dudley!
He cut off her penis!
What the hell?
Wait. what?
Is she getting dressed already?
Let me show you
how it's done. Pinocchio.
Come here. you filthy slut.
And eat this stupid stick!
And give me that!
What are you doing?
That ass!
It'll make you scream!
Kid. little boys
never give up.
Come back!
Amanda!
Damn.
What a fucking dog he is!
Really?
It's me.
No. forget it!
A golden train!
And lots of little dolls!
Help!
You're not going to take James away from me!
No. that's not what I meant!
You can't
pick on James anymore.
It's too late for lies now.
You're my best friend.
You're a really nice guy.
I don't want to kill you!
Cricket one. bald old hag zero.
We're at least
ten minutes away.
And if he... Shit!
Shit. shit. shit.
We already have enough
problems. James.
What the hell?
Hi. Grandpa.
Where are you?
We just made a quick stop.
But I had to...
Bill!
No. no!
We're trying to beat him to it!
I know where
his next target lives.
Dudley!
Give it to me for five.
I know what I have to do.
So. what do you say?
Yeah... he definitely won't suspect
a thing tonight.
Shit.
I remember when you were
a little piece of wood
And now... you are
handsome and complete.
Finally.
A real boy.
Why are you sulking. kid?
Boy?
I'm gorgeous.
Could it be that...
...does it suit me. Pinok?
Look. Dad.
I made a puppet. too.
Is that
your grandfather's car?
Yes.
Let's go.
There are more on the way.
Look!
Hurry. Mia! Catch up to him!
Hold on to the handrails!
They wanted to hurt James.
Why?
That old liar!
You lied to me.
Why did you lie to me?
You ruined everything.
my little stick.
It's all your fault.
You carved out
this path all by yourself.
You forced me to do all
those horrible things.
You won't fool me again.
How pitiful.
You were never satisfied
with who you are.
I should have been
in your place.
Look at me when I'm talking to you!
You made everyone hate me.
Why are you so mean. Pinocchio?
Just as evil as those
you slaughtered.
We raised you.
Come on. be a good boy. Pinocchio.
Kill him. Cricket.
There he is.
No!
Leave him alone!
There's something I need
to show you.
You want to be true to yourself
because of who you used to be.
Come with me.
What is this place?
This is where you were created.
Oh my God...
It draws its nourishment from its roots.
It grows as it absorbs
their life energy.
And he channels it into the wood.
The same wood that I later collect myself.
Exactly.
You owe your very existence to them.
When their lives came to an end.
yours began.
Where did they come from?
As soon as I realized that I could
collect it myself. I began to study them.
Trying to understand
how they worked.
To refine the process.
There have been many failures.
It's moving.
One of them was
particularly dangerous.
That's why I was forced
to keep her imprisoned.
And then you showed up.
My perfect creation.
You had tremendous potential.
Features?
What for?
Prove that I was right.
That we can be reborn.
That we can
defeat death.
But in the end. you turned out to be
just as much of a failure as the rest of them.
Your grandfather
is a murderer. James.
What can we do
when faced with a murderer?
Are you absolutely sure?
Yes.
We can't just
wait.
He doesn't deserve to die. okay?
James... maybe it's better this way.
I agree. Dudley is right.
He did it to protect me!
I'm not taking part in this.
Whatever you want!
Then stay here!
That's strange...
We both wanted to become
just like each other.
Who am I descended from?
From a little boy.
A good friend of James's.
Zack?
So I came from...
What on earth?
I was hoping that
Zack's friendship with James.
would prove that death
is not the end.
That's enough.
This is going from
bad to worse.
I'm going to the police.
Your grandpa is a monster.
But I don't want to die.
Your death is the
best thing that could happen to James
No!
You damn kid!
I don't have time for you right now.
We have to save him.
Hurry up.
Look here.
James!
One!
My dad has gone crazy!
I know.
I don't want you to die.
You're in danger.
James!
One!
Stop! No!
I know a place where we can hide.
No!
Come on!
We have to go!
James!
They must die!
Wait for me!
And I'll bring Mia back. too.
James... I did all of this for you.
No.
You didn't do it for me.
That's what you wanted.
Did you think no one would
ever find out the truth?
Come on.
Come on. boys and girls.
I am on the verge of a
great discovery.
Something greater than all of us.
No... I can't.
Dr. Gallow showed me
how to bring you back.
No!
You ruined everything!
What the hell?
You forget who you are.
I created you.
I'm not your puppet anymore.
You are.
Without me. you're
just a piece of wood.
No. I'm more than that.
A puppet needs a master.
and only I can make you real.
Let me make you just like James.
I don't want
to be like James anymore.
I just want to be myself.
You'll always feel empty inside.
Incomplete.
Broken.
Maybe...
But you can't
control me anymore.
I gave you life.
I'm not just
your father. Pinocchio.
I am your god.
And your god just
killed a god.
Go fuck yourself.
Goodbye.
Oh God...
James?
Are we still friends?
Am I... bad?
You were just confused.
Just... don't do that again. okay?
I'm such an idiot...
Yeah... after all. we all make mistakes.
Except for my dentist.
I'll need a new one.
I'll find you someone else.
You won't tell
anyone about me. will you?
And you won't lie.
Great.
Me neither.
Me?
Let's go.
We left.
I'll beat you to it.
Goodbye. Father.
You created me.
but you don't control me anymore.
James is my friend.
No!
Don't kill me!
I didn't want to kill
all of them.
Dialogue Translation &
Timing: Sparta